Anglo-American Council on Productivity Pamphlets 5334
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Anglo-American Council on Productivity Pamphlets
1951-1993
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Anglo-American Council on Productivity
5334
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Records (documents), pamphlets.
Pamphlets created by the Anglo-American Council on Productivity.
5599269
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, July 02, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Anglo-American Council on Productivity was formed in the Autumn of 1948 on the initiative of Sir Stafford Cripps, the Chancellor of the Exchequer in Eritian, and Mr. Paul Hoffman, the Economic Cooperation Administrator in the U.S.A.
It is composed of representatives of management and labor both in the United Kingdom and in the United States of America. In the United Kingdom section the constituent bodies are the Federation of British Industries, the British Employers' Confederation and the Trades Union Congress.
The purpose of the Council was to promote economic well-being by a free exchange of knowledge in the realm of industrial organisation, method and technique and thereby to assist British industry to raise the level of its productivity.
The principal means adopted to achieve this end was to send to America industrial Teams, the members of which were drawn in equal numbers from the supervisory, the technical, and the workshop levels. The business of the Teams was to study American production methods, to report their observations and findings and to make recommendations.
Each Team went out as an independent body and was solely responsible for its report. Team visits were completed in 1952. The work of following up on the reports was transferred to the British Productivity Council, and the Anglo-American Council was dissolved as of June 30, 1952.
Scope and Contents
Pamphlets created by the Anglo-American Council on Productivity.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Industrial relations -- Great Britain; Industrial relations -- United States; Great Britain -- Economic policy; United States -- Economic policy; Industrial productivity -- Great Britain; Industrial productivity -- United States; Industrial organization -- Great Britain; Industrial organization -- United States; Anglo-American Council on Productivity.
5599269
- A, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Ammunition, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Productivity Team. Report of a British Productivity Team on Ammunition which visited the United States of America in 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: As the Spirit Moves: Case Studies in Materials Handling, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By British Productivity Council. Item is in English.
- B [Folder 1 of 2], 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The Brassfoundry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the British Brassfounding Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The British Cotton Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By United States Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team from the United States of America which visited the United Kingdom in 1951. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The British Electricity System, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By United States Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team from the United States of America which visited the United Kingdom in 1952. Item is in English.
- B [Folder 2 of 2], 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The Britsh Pressed Metal Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Brushes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the British Brush Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Building, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Building Industry. Item is in English.
- C, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Cakes and Biscuits, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Productivity Team representing the British Cake and Biscuit Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Coal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Coal Mining Industry which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
- Cotton, 1993; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Cotton Spinning, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Cotton Spinning Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Cotton Weaving, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Cotton Weaving Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Cotton Yarn Doubling, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Cotton Yarn Doubling Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Summary of Productivity Team Report: Cotton Spinning, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Item is in English.
- D, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Design for Production, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1952 of a British Specialist Team on Design for Production. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Diesel Locomotives, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Diesel Locomotive Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Diesel Locomotives, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Diesel Locomotive Industry. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Drop Forging, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Drop Forging Industry. Item is in English.
- E, 1973; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Education for Management, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Specialist Team concerned with Education for Management. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Electric Motor Control Gear and Small Airbrake Swithchgear, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing sections of the Electrical Manufacturing Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Electric Motor Control Gear and Small Airbrake Swithchgear, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Electricity Supply, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing Electricity Supply Industry. Item is in English.
- F [Folder 1 of 2], 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Food Canning, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Productivity Team representing the British Food Canning Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Footwear, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the British Footwear Industry. Item is in English.
- F [Folder 2 of 2], 1951-1985; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Freight Handling, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Specialist Team which visited the United States of America in 1950. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Fruit and Vegetable Storage and Pre-Packaging, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 by a Specialist Team on Fruit and Vegetable Storage and Pre-Packaging. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Fruit and Vegetable Utilisation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a British Productivity Team on Fruit and Vegetable Utilisation. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Fuel Conservation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1952 by a Specialist Team on the Conservation of Fuel, Heat and Energy. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Furniture, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Productivity Team representing the British Furniture Industry. Item is in English.
- G [Folder 1 of 2], Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Gas, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Gas Industry which visited the United States of America in 1952. Item is in English.
- G [Folder 2 of 2], 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Grey Ironfounding, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Grey Ironfounding Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Grey Ironfounding, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Grey Ironfounding Industry. Copy 2. Item is in English.
- H, 1952-1993; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Heavy Chemicals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Heavy Chemical Industry, which visited the United States of America in 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Hop Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. and Canada in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Hop Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Hosiery and Knitwear, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the United States of America in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Hosiery and Knitwear Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Hot Dip Galvanizing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Specialist Team representing the Hot Dip Galvanizing Industry. Item is in English.
- I, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Iron and Steel, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Iron and Steel Industry which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Inspection in Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Specialist Team on Inspection Methods in Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Internal Combustion Engines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Internal Combustion Engine Industry. Item is in English.
- L, 1952-1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Letterpress Printing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Letterpress Printing Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Lithographic Printing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Productivity Team representing the British Lithographic Printing Industry. Item is in English.
- M [Folder 1 of 2], 1952-1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Management Accounting, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a Specialist Team which visited the United States of America in 1950. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Materials Handling in Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Summary of a Report on the investigation in the United States of America made by a team appointed by the Anglo-American Council on Productivity. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Meat Packing and Processing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Meat Packing and Processing Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Men's Clothing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the United States of America in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Men's and Youth's Factory-Tailored Clothing Industry. Item is in English.
- M [Folder 2 of 2], 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Metal Finishing, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Specialist Team representing the British Metal Finishing Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Metalworking Machine Tools, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Machine Tool Industry which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Milk Utilisation, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a British Productivity Team which visited the United States of America in 1952 to study the utilisation of milk. Item is in English.
- N, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Non-Ferrous Metals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Wrought Non-Ferrous Metals Industry. Item is in English.
- P [Folder 1 of 3], 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Packaging, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 2: Packet Food, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Productivity Team representing the British Packet Foods Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Pharmaceuticals, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Pharmaceutical Industry. Item is in English.
- P [Folder 2 of 3], 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Plant Maintenace, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1952 by a Specialist Team on Plant Maintenance. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Plastics Moulding, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Plastics Moulding Industry which visited the United States of America in 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Pressed Metal, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Pressed Metal Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Production Control, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Specialist Team on Production Planning and Control. Item is in English.
- P [Folder 3 of 3], 1953; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Production in Farming, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Farming Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Productivity Measurement in British Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Specialist Team. A Symposium of Papers by authors with first-hand experience of its benefits. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Productivity Measurement in British Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Specialist Team. A Symposium of Papers by authors with first-hand experience of its benefits. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Provincial Press, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Provincial Press which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
- R, 1951; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Rayon Weaving, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Rayon Weaving Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Retailing, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing British Retailing which visited the United States of America in 1952. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Rigid Boxes and Cartona, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Rigid Boxes and Cartons Industry. Item is in English.
- S, 1952-1990; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Simplification in British Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Report of an inquiry in Britain by the Group appointed by the Council, which made an investigation of simplification in the United States of America. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Simplification in Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Report of an investigation in the United States of America made by a group appointed by the Council. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Simplification in Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Report of an investigation in the United States of America made by a group appointed by the Council. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Steel Construction, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1951 of a Productivity Team on Construction Steelwork, Fabricated Platework, and Mechanical Handling Plant. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Steel Founding, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Steel Founding Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Superphosphate and Compound Fertilizers, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1949 of a Productivity Team representing the Fertilizer Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Saving Scarce Materials, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Specialist Team. Report of a Specialist Team which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
- T, 1952; Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Trade Unions and Productivity, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    By British Trade Union Officials. Report and Recommendations of a team of British Trade Union Officials who investigated the role of unions in increasing productivity in the United States of America. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Training of Operatives, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    By Specialist Team. Report of one of four Specialist Teams which visited the United States of America in 1951 to study the problems of training for industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Training of Operatives, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    By Specialist Team. Report of one of four Specialist Teams which visited the United States of America in 1951 to study the problems of training for industry. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Training of Operatives, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    By Specialist Team. Report of one of four Specialist Teams which visited the United States of America in 1951 to study the problems of training for industry. Copy 3. Item is in English.
- Y-Z, 1951-1953; Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Universities and Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Valves, Steel, Iron and Non-Ferrous, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a visit to the U.S.A. in 1950 of a Productivity Team representing the Valve Industry. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Welding, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Woodworking Machinery, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Woodworking Industry which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Zinc and Aluminium Die Casting, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    By Productivity Team. Report of a Productivity Team representing the British Zinc and Aluminium Die Casting Industry which visited the United States of America in 1951. Item is in English.
- Final Report and Catalogue, 1951; Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The Final Report of the Council, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
    By Anglo-American Council on Productivity. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Catalogue of Productivity Reports, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)